Hi hi hi again
We cool now
Why because to your point there's community there's a sense of pride about you know what I got to go honor my parents back in Nigeria
I'm heart Nigerian. I have to go honor my parents. I have to go honor my elders
They're not twerking and shaking booty. They're getting they are literally twerking and shaking and I know I ain't doing it
We literally learned it from Africa
They're doctors twerking and shaking so maybe they can shake because they got the money to back it up
But do you see what you're saying? Do you see what I'm saying though? We have to be honest Amanda
Well as a fellow daughter of an immigrant, right? So my mother's from Grenada
My mother did come here and was able to work and was able to get green cards for folks
So shout out to my mom. There's a very big difference in growing up somewhere and coming from a place where you are the majority
And where your people are running the show than being somewhere where your people have been subjugated the entire time
Your people have been here. But your mama came here and she wasn't the majority. So how did she succeed?
She succeeded because she came here with the fortitude of coming from a place
Her resilience, right?
No, but you're
Let me say what I'm saying
Okay, I'll let you unpack
If we don't acknowledge divide and conquer in the United States, we are having a pointless conversation
I agree
We have to acknowledge that there is a concerted effort at divide and conquer in the United States
We're literally watching it happen right now with an effort to divide and conquer and have black people fighting immigrants
And have black people saying that immigrants don't matter
And fighting white people
White people is not the point
The concept of white people is about people who are upholding as a supremacy of whiteness versus people who understand that there should be an egalitarianism
There should be an equality
We are becoming the new white supremacist
We are
We've been putting them on a pedestal
We feel like we can't do anything
No, it's not that we're putting them on a pedestal
It's that we are joining them and instead weaponizing our blackness against our people
When we do what you're saying
We are saying
I am better
Because I can
I figured it out
And so you're the problem
Because you didn't figure it out
But Amanda, what about if I believe that the American dream is
I have a right to that as well
Is that me joining white people?
Or is that me saying, you know what?
What's the American dream?
The American dream for me
Because it may look different from other people
Some people it's a boss chick
For me, I want my kids to grow up in a wonderful neighborhood
I want them to go to college
I want to have a 401k
I want to do this
I want to do that
So I feel like a lot of times in the black community
We associate anything that's right or that's just
Or that's striving forward with whiteness
So when you say that we're working with them
Well no, it's not that it's whiteness
It's capitalism
And I think that's what we have to understand the difference of
The concept of capitalism always is grounded in exploitation
And I think that's what we have to do